<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Luis Selvera</title>
    <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Luis Selvera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ldselvera.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Federated Transformer Log Learning for Threat Forensics</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tad/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Threat detection and forensics have become an imperative component in every digital forensic triage. Supervised approaches have been proposed for inferring system and network anomalies; including anomaly detection contributions using syslogs. Nevertheless, most works downplay the importance of the interpretability of a model&amp;rsquo;s decision-making process. In this research, we are among the first to propose an interpretable federated transformer log learning model for threat detection supporting explainable cyber forensics. The proposed model is generated by training a local transformer-based threat detection model at each client in an organizational unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantized Spectral Clustering with Seq2Seq Attention Model to Predict Cognitive State from Behavior Variables</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tsd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Human behavior is a reflection of brain activity, and brain disorders often result in abnormal behavior. Traditionally, interventions for brain disorders focus on either behavior, such as psychotherapy, or brain (e.g. medication, surgery), but not both. There are benefits of utilizing both brain and behavior modalities, such as early detection, treatment monitoring, and use of precision medicine to take into account individual differences. However, the central challenge in multimodal behavior and neurocognitive learning involves learning representations that can process and relate information from both modalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multivariate Time Series Representation Learning on Zeek Logs for Network Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/nids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/nids/</guid>
      <description>This talk looked at Liberty Mutual’s transformation to Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, and DevOps. For a large, heavily regulated industry, this task can not only be daunting, but viewed by many as impossible. Often, organizations try to reduce the friction through micro-fixes, but Eddie’s team asked how to change the culture to reduce the friction and concluded with the following final points:
 Don’t mandate DevOps. Give employees the chance to master their discipline with examples to set and follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Covid-19 through Social Media using Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/covid/</guid>
      <description>•	Worked in team of 7 implementing data pipeline to process unstructured text data from Twitter and Google
•	Developed data preprocessing and analytics modules to cleanse and gain insight from collected dataset
•	Developing text classification sentiment analysis deployed on website using Django web framework</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection using Encoder-Decoder Temporal Convolutional Network (ED-TCN)</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/fraud/</guid>
      <description>•	Implemented deep learning solution to detecting credit card frauds using sequential ED-TCN model
•	Developed model using Keras achieving a 96% accuracy
•	Presented project in RowdyHacks Hackathon workshop session with 40 attendees</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-based Classification of Questions on Q&amp;A Forums using Bi-LSTM</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/tutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/tutor/</guid>
      <description>•	Developed Bidirectional-LSTM model to detect improper questions using datasets from Q&amp;amp;A forums
•	Deployed model on website using Flask web framework for users to input their questions for classifications
•	Developed model using Pytorch achieving a 97% classification accuracy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trolls Detector using Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT)</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/trolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/trolls/</guid>
      <description>•	Implemented deep learning solution to detecting trolls online using sequential BERT model for classification
•	Built website that uses model to detect trolls on forums websites allowing users to input the posts
•	Developed model using Pytorch and deployed on website using Flask web framework</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutor Tools Software</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/projects/creations/question/</guid>
      <description>•	Built a software application for tutoring services using Java and MySQL
•	Applied software engineering principles, Agile Method, and software design patter model-view-controller (MVC)
•	Allows tutors and students to manage tutoring sessions and give a visual organization of the collected information</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
