<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Submitted for Publication on Luis Selvera</title>
    <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submitted for Publication on Luis Selvera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Federated Transformer Log Learning for Threat Forensics</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tad/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Threat detection and forensics have become an imperative component in every digital forensic triage. Supervised approaches have been proposed for inferring system and network anomalies; including anomaly detection contributions using syslogs. Nevertheless, most works downplay the importance of the interpretability of a model&amp;rsquo;s decision-making process. In this research, we are among the first to propose an interpretable federated transformer log learning model for threat detection supporting explainable cyber forensics. The proposed model is generated by training a local transformer-based threat detection model at each client in an organizational unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantized Spectral Clustering with Seq2Seq Attention Model to Predict Cognitive State from Behavior Variables</title>
      <link>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldselvera.github.io/publications/tsd/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Human behavior is a reflection of brain activity, and brain disorders often result in abnormal behavior. Traditionally, interventions for brain disorders focus on either behavior, such as psychotherapy, or brain (e.g. medication, surgery), but not both. There are benefits of utilizing both brain and behavior modalities, such as early detection, treatment monitoring, and use of precision medicine to take into account individual differences. However, the central challenge in multimodal behavior and neurocognitive learning involves learning representations that can process and relate information from both modalities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
